Guide to the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Irish Americana Collection AIA.031.004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Sheet Music (Irish), 1817-1995
  - Accretions
    - My Wild Irish Rose, undated (Box 62, Folder 32)
    - My Mary's Heart is Irish, 1907 (Box 62, Folder 33)
    - Molly Me Own, 1916 (Box 62, Folder 34)
    - Micky, 1918 (Box 62, Folder 35)
    - Ragged Robin, 1904 (Box 62, Folder 36)
    - Memories of Ireland, 1919 (Box 62, Folder 37)
    - McAlheeny's Cake Walk, 1899 (Box 62, Folder 38)
    - Mary Houlihan, 1916 (Box 62, Folder 39)
    - Molly O', 1916 (Box 62, Folder 40)
    - Love At Last, 1913 (Box 62, Folder 41)
    - Live My Love, Oh Live, 1885 (Box 62, Folder 42)
    - A Little Bit of Irish, 1911 (Box 62, Folder 43)
    - Let Me Glance At Dear Old Ireland Once Again, 1911 (Box 62, Folder 45)
    - Those Good Old Days Back Home, 1916 (Box 62, Folder 47)
    - There's A Long, Long Trail, 1915 (Box 62, Folder 48)
    - Sweet Rosie O'Grady, 1924 (Box 62, Folder 49)
    - Sweet Innis Fallen, 1909 (Box 62, Folder 50)
    - The Last of the Rohans, 1899 (Box 62, Folder 51)
    - Smiling Irish Eyes, 1929 (Box 62, Folder 52)
    - Sligo (Just to Hear My Mother Sing), 1920 (Box 62, Folder 53)
    - She's A Flower from the Fields of Old Ireland, 1909 (Box 62, Folder 54)
    - My Irish Rosie, 1906 (Box 62, Folder 55)
    - Well! The Irish and the Germans Got Together, 1928 (Box 62, Folder 56)
    - My Irish Prairie Queen, 1909 (Box 62, Folder 57)
    - The Mulligan Guard, 1873 (Box 62, Folder 58)
    - My Name is Kelly (But I'm Livin' the Life of Reilly), 1919 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 10)
    - I Love To Hear A Good Old Irish Song, 1909 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 11)
    - Th' Breath of An Irish Smile, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 12)
    - The Heart of Paddy Whack, 1914 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 13)
    - Irish Beauties - Two Step, 1911 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 14)
    - I Never See Maggie Alone, 1926 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 15)
    - I'm On My Way to Dublin Bay, 1915 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 16)
    - I'll Buy the Blarney Castle, 1920 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 17)
    - Little Isle O'Green, 1913 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 18)
    - Ragged Robin, 1908 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 19)
    - The Old Irish Mother of Mine (Piano Reel), 1920 (Box 64)
- Series II: Songsters and Song Albums, 1863-1960
  Series II: Songsters and Song Albums, 1863-1960 consists of songsters (songbooks) and song albums containing both Irish and Irish-American content. These range in date from 1863's Irish Song Album with Various Artists to Irish Favorites (1960), with the majority published between 1900 and 1940. There are a number of undated examples, especially among the pocket-sized songsters which most likely were published in the middle of the nineteenth century. Many of the items in this series illustrate stereotyped depictions of the Irish and other ethnic groups in the nineteenth century. Most are in excellent condition and many contain handwritten music, annotations, and signatures. The songsters in particular lend themselves to a comparison of nineteenth-century stereotypes of the Irish as well as Jewish, German (Gus Williams Sdill I Don't Vas Happy Songster, Box 5, Folder 6), and African-American (Harry Pell's Ebony Songster, Box 5, Folder 4) figures.
  - 50 Beauties of Erin, undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - 12 New Charming Irish Songs, 1954 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Airs and Fantasies, 1932 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Album of Irish Diamonds, nd, 1910 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Album of Songs by Victor Herbert, 1927 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Ancient Irish Music, undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Beadle's Dime Songbook No. 4, 1859 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Beadle's Dime Songbook No. 5, 1860 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Beadle's Dime Songbook No. 7, 1860 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Beadle's Singer's Library, 1878 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Bing Crosby – Dance Folio - Carmel Quinn, 1933 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Carmel Quinn (2), post-1955 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - The Catharine Hayes' Songster, undated (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Cavan O'Connor's Favourites, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Chappell's Famous Melodies, 1934 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - The Charly O'Malley Irish Comic Songster, 1862 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Choice Irish Songs, Vol. II, 1906 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Dance Music for Teaching and Concert Purposes, undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Echoes from Erin, 1926 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Echoes from Ireland, 1926 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Emerald Gems, 1940 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Famous Irish Songs, 1930 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Favorite Irish Melodies of Thomas Moore, The, 1906 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Favorite Irish Songs, 1943 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Favorite Songs of Ireland, 1909 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Favorite Reels, Jigs, and Hornpipes, 1907 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Greatest of All Irish Songs, 1942, 1945, 1949 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Harding's Collection of Jigs, Reels, & c., 1928 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Harrigan and Hart's Patrick's Day Parade Songster, 1874 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Harry & John Kernell's Irish Specialties Songster, undated (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Hermit Songs, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - I'm Forever Blowing Bubbles Songster, undated (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Ireland's Kings, 1896 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Ireland's Own Song Book, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Irish Album of Songs, 1955, 1957 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Irish All-Time Hits, 1951 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Irish Ballad Album, post-1892 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Irish Ballads, Jigs, and Reels Songbooks, 1943, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Irish Come-All-Ye's, c. 1931 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Irish Favorites, 1960 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Irish Gems- Waltzes, 1906 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Irish Jigs, Songs, and Dances, 1937 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Irish Song Album, undated (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Irish Song Albums, 1899 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Irish Song Album with Various Artists, 1863 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Irish Song and Joke, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Irish Song Collection, 1954, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Irish Songs, 1937 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Irish Songs and Airs, 1936 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Irish Songs and Ballads, 1916 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Irish Songs, Jigs, and Reels, 1943 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Irish Songster, undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Irish Songs, Vol. I, 1908 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Jigs and Reels, Vol. I, 1908 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Jigs and Reels, Vol. II, 1908 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Jigs, Reels, and Country Dances, 1933 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Johnny Paterson's Irish Clown Songster, undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Melodies of Ireland, 1885 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Melody Mike's Favorite Irish Songs, 1908 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Old Fashioned Minstrel Show - Gilbert, 1902 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Old Time Jigs and Reels, 1906 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - O'Neill's Dance Music of Ireland, 1910 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Overture of Irish Melodies, 1909 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Scanlan's Famous Songs, 1924 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Six Hundred and Seventeen Irish Songs and Ballads, undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Sixty Irish Songs (Copy 1), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Sixty Irish Songs (Copy 2), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Sixty Irish Songs (Copy 3), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Songs By A Turf Fire, 1956 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Summer Time is the Time for Me Songster, 1892 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - The Alliance Songster, 1891 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Bassett's Native Herb Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Campfire Songster, The, 1862 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Christy's New Songster and Black Jokes, 1863 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Cole and Lockwood Songster, The, undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Comic Songs, Funny Stories and Recitations, 1928 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Comic Songster No. XXII, 1839 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Comical Brown's Songster, 1885 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Don't Go Mollie Darling Songster, The, 1872 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - E J Hassan's One of the Finest Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Fenian Song Book, undated (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Ferguson and Mack's Political Candidates Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Grandfather's Clock Songster, 1877 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Gus William's Sdill I Don't Vas Happy Songster, 1872 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Happy Billy Radcliffe's Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Happy Dick Turner's Sea Side Aquarium Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Harry Pell's Ebony Songster, 1864 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Howorth's Hibernica Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Irish Peasant Songs, 1922 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Katie Cooper's Cindy Jane Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Kome and Kiss Me Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Lannigan's Ball Songster, 1863 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Lookout Mountain No. Two Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Minstrel Show Guide, undated (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - My Country 'Tis of Thee: Republican Song Book, 1880 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - Pat Rooney's Is That Mr. Reilly Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - Patriotic American Songs, 1909 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Patterson's Ideal Songster (3 copies), undated (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Rody the Rover Songster and Emerald Isle Lecture Book, 1873 (Box 48, Folder 29)
  - Schoolcraft and Coe's Mrs. Diddimus' Party Songster, 1881 (Box 48, Folder 30)
  - Sentimental Songs for the Lady's [sic], undated (Box 48, Folder 31)
  - Shaughraun Songster, The, 1875 (Box 48, Folder 32)
  - Squatter Sovereignty Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 33)
  - Swim Out for Glory Songster, 1882 (Box 48, Folder 34)
  - Tall Corn Songster, The, undated (Box 48, Folder 35)
  - Walter L Main Circus-Show's Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 36)
  - W H Power's Ivy Leaf Songster, undated (Box 48, Folder 37)
  - Sullivan & Harrington's Mighty Rapid Liza Songster, undated (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Johnny Roach's Variety Combination Songster, undated (Box 58, Folder 14)
- Series III: Sheet Music (Non-Irish), 1847-1950
  Series III: Sheet Music (Non-Irish), 1847-1946 consists of sheet music that does not specifically pertain to Irish America, but are nonetheless significant examples from the vaudeville and Tin Pan Alley era. The approximate date range for these materials is circa 1847 to 1946. Some of the sheet music found within this series include minstrel songs that include offensive imagery and language regarding Black people.
  The materials in this series are arranged alphabetically by song title, with the exception of materials from accession 2010-019, housed in Box 63 and Shared Tamiment 164, which were not arranged by an archivist and added to the end of the previously created alphabetized file listings.
  - A Cavalry Catch, 1913 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - A Dream, 1923 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Ah! Sweet Mystery of Life, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - An Outcast, 1898 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Beautiful Dreamer, 1936 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Beautiful Face of Jennie Knott, The, 1894 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Belle of Manayunk Waltz, 1904 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Broomstick Buckaroo, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - By the Lone Riverside, 1862 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Carry Me Back to Old Virginny, 1906 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Complete Minstrel Folio, post-1933 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Corn Flower Waltz, undated (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Day Dreams, 1906 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - 'E Dunno Know Where 'E Are, 1895 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Fairy Bell Waltz, The, 1890 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Florie's First Waltz, 1871 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Four Little Blackberries, 1907 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Four Little Curly Headed Coons, 1891 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Get a Girl to Love You, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Golf Club, The, 1900 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Harpist's Dream, 1873 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - I Believe in Miracles, 1934 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - I'll Meet You When the Roses Bloom Again, undated (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - I'm Afraid of the Beautiful Girls, 1916 (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Immigration Rose (Smile Again, Kathleen Mavourneen), 1923 (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - In the Palace of Dreams, 1914 (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - Jolly Beggar, The, undated (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Jolly Jack March, 1900 (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Just a Girl That Men Forget, 1923 (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Just Like a Gipsy, 1919 (Box 49, Folder 31)
  - Love Days, 1908 (Box 49, Folder 32)
  - Lurline, Do You Think of Me Now?, 1881 (Box 49, Folder 33)
  - Mighty Lak' a Rose, 1924 (Box 49, Folder 34)
  - Minstrel Songster, 1911 (Box 49, Folder 35)
  - Mission of a Rose, The, 1895 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Moon, the Coon, and the little Octoroon, 1903 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Music of the Ethiopian Serenaders, 1847 (?) (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - My Bonnie, 1936 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - North Country, 1893 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Old Black Joe, undated (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Old Folks at Home, 1897 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Oh, Johnny! Oh, Johnny! Oh!, 1917 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - O! Sing to Me, undated (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Precious Treasure, 1894 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Red Lips, 1874 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Shine On Harvest Moon, 1908, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - That Mellow Melody, 1912 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - That Naughty Waltz, 1920 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Thinking of Home and Mother, 1894 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Uncle Sammie's Boys, 1942 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Violette, 1905 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Turn Back the Universe and Give Me Yesterday, 1916 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Where Did You Get That Hat?, 1888 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - When Francis Dances With Me, 1921 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - When Grandma Sings the Songs She Loved at the End of a Perfect Day, 1916 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - When It's Apple Blossom Time in Normandie, 1912 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - When That Little Yellow Fellow Plays Piano, 1915 (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - When You Come Back, 1918 (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - When You Sit Beside the Fireside in Winter, 1915 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Who Do You Love?, 1918 (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - Who Paid the Rent for Mrs. Rip Van Winkle?, 1914 (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Without You, 1918 (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - You'll Always Be the Same Sweet Girl, 1915 (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - You'll miss me, Darling Chloe, 1878 (Box 50, Folder 30)
  - You're as Welcome as the Flowers in May, 1942 (Box 50, Folder 31)
  - Zaza, Come On The Piazza, 1910 (Box 50, Folder 32)
  - Indian Summer, 1939 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - I'm On My Way to Mandalay, 1913 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Missouri Waltz, 1914 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Alexander's Ragtime Band, 1911 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Aloha Oe Waltzes, 1915 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Be My Little Baby Bumble Bee, 1912 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Blue Hawaii, 1945 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Brian Boru March, 1896 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Come Over to Dover, 1914 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - For You, undated (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - On the Hoko Moko Isle, 1916 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Nights of Gladness, 1912 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - My Isle of Golden Dreams, 1919 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Lullaby of Broadway, 1950 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - My Aloha Land, 1939 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - You Made Me Love You (I Didn't Want to Do It), 1913 (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Waters of the Perkiomen, 1925 (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Under the Double Eagle, 1944 (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaenous I, undated (Box 63, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaenous II, undated (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - Polkas, Schottisches, etc… (Irish Washer Woman), undated (Box 63, Folder 22)
  - Try This Over On Your Piano, Boy Scout, 1911 (Box 63, Folder 23)
  - Zephyr, 1889 (Box 63, Folder 24)
  - A Wonderful Thing, 1914 (Box 63, Folder 25)
  - Brahms Compositions for the Piano, 1926 (Box 63, Folder 26)
  - McNeil Chord System, 1923 (Box 63, Folder 27)
  - Butterly Dance, 1918 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 5)
  - Call Me Back Again, 1881 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 6)
  - Uncle Tom's Cabin, 1914 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 7)
  - Fancy Nancy Clancy, 1922 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 8)
  - Come On Over Here It's a Wonderful Place, 1916 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Joke Books, 1883-1928
  Series IV: Joke Books, 1883-1928 includes books that record racial and ethnic stereotyples of Irish, Jewish, and Black people that were commonly used in Vaudeville performances and minstrel shows in the 19th and early 20th centuries. The Irish were a popular subject of mockery in the vaudville shows of the mid 19th century in response to the arrival of the first large wave of Irish immigrants in the United States. As the decades passed and large immigrant groups from other places in the world arrived in the US, Irish Americans often performed in vaudeville acts that mocked people of other ethnicities and performed in black-face at minstrel shows.
  - Burdett's Irish Dialect, Recitations and Readings, 1883 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Cooper's Irish Dialect Readings and Recitations, 1891 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Irish Jokes, No. 1, 1906 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Choice Irish Jokes No. 3, 1907 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Irish Yarns No. 1 [ 2 copies], 1907 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Irish Jokes No. 2, 1907 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Hebrew Jokes No. 1, 1908 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Jew Jokes and Job Lots, 1908 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - New Book of Monologues, 1908 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - A Minstrel Guide and Joke Book, 1912 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Irish Jokes No. 3 (Wehman), 1914 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Combination Irish Hebrew and Dutch Jokes, 1916 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Irish Wit and Humor, 1918 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Baker's Minstrel Joke Book, 1928 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Comical Sayings of Paddy from Cork, The, undated (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Harrigan & Hart's New York Boys Joker, undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Irish Assassin, or the Misfortunes of the Family of O'Donnel, The, undated (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Irish Yarns No. 2 Wit and Humor (3 copies), undated (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Selected Vaudeville Jokes, undated (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Star Series of Irish Yarns Fun Wit and Humor, The, undated (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Surprising Life and Adventures of the Gentlemen-Robber, Redmond O'Hanlon, The, undated (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - Witty and Extravagant Exploits of George Buchanan to Which is Added the Comical Sayings of Paddy from Cork, The, undated (Box 51, Folder 21)
- Series V: Postcards, 1900-1915
  Series V: Postcards, 1900-1915 consists of postcards produced for both the St. Patrick's Day market and tourism to Ireland. Dr. Moloney arranged the cards by theme in eleven categories: St. Patrick's Day, Colleens, Dance, Holiday (Irish, but not March 17th), Humor, Irish-America, Irish Scenes, Irish (general), Music, Pipes, and Miscellaneous. This is the largest known collection of its kind in the world, and includes examples from German, English, and American manufacturers such as Raphael Tuck and Sons and the International Art Publishing Co., and prominent postcard artists such as Ellen H. Clapsaddle. Of particular interest are cards that depict dual loyalties to Ireland as well as the United States and those that incorporate specific locations in Ireland such as Blarney Castle or the Lakes of Killarney.
  - St. Patrick's Day, undated (Box 52, Folder 1-400, Box 53, Folder SPD 401-455, Box 59, Folder 1-2)
  - Colleens, undated (Box 53, Folder C 1-18)
  - Dance, undated (Box 53, Folder D 1-16)
  - Holiday, undated (Box 53, Folder H 1-21)
  - Humour, undated (Box 53, Folder Hr 1-61)
  - Irish-American, undated (Box 53, Folder IA 1-28)
  - Irish Scenes, undated (Box 53, Folder IS 1-49)
  - Irish (General), undated (Box 53, Folder I 1-129)
  - Music, undated (Box 53, Folder M 1-20)
  - Pipes, undated (Box 53, Folder P 1-5)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 53, Folder Mi 1-18, Box 59, Folder 3)
- Series VI: Ephemera, 1833-1961
  Series VI: Ephemera, 1856-1960 consists of cartoons, advertisements, and other examples of Irish-American imagery from journalism and marketing. Of particular interest are illustrations published in Harper's Weekly and Puck from the 1860s and 1870s, as well as cigar-box art from the late nineteenth century, and print advertisements for Irish International Airlines, Jameson's Irish Whiskey, and Coca-Cola published in the middle of the twentieth century.
  - Sub-series VI.A: General, 1833-1961
    - Academy of Music Irish Famine Relief Fund Special Programme, 1880 (Box 58, Folder 22)
    - "Ashore" (Print), 1889 (Box 58, Folder 23)
    - Association of Irish Musicians, Philadelphia, flyer, Aug 24, 1957 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - BF Keith Palace Theatre Program Magazine, 1926 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Bookmarks (10), undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Broth of a Boy (misc), undated (Box 55, Folder 31)
    - Buttons, undated (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Cartes de Visite (5), 1893, undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Cottages (2) (photos), undated (Box 55, Folder 32)
    - Courant, Supplemen t. Hartford, CT, Apr 5, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 57)
    - Federation of American Societies for Irish Independence, News Bulletin, Oct 11, 1949 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Feis Eireann, 1955 (Box 55, Drawer 27)
    - Friends of Irish Freedom Card, 1916 (Box 58, Folder 21)
    - Gaelic American (photostats of individual pages), 1904-1932 (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
    - Galeophone (book of Irish text and English translation), 1910 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Great Irish Musician's Union Ball, Philadelphia, program, May 29, 1953 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Greeting Cards (16), undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - The Illustrated History of the Mulligan Guard, 1874 (Box 58, Folder 24)
    - Ireland's National Feis: Ladies Day in Harvest, Harp and Shamrock Club of Chicago, program, Aug 15, 1946 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Irish Airs - Victor Records Program, undated (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - Irish-American Annual Dance, Philadelphia, program, Dec 15, 1945 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Irish Book Shop, New York City, catalogue, circa 1950s (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Irish Festival Music Programs, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Irish Musical Association of Philadelphia, program, Feb 18, 1947 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Irish Musicians Union, Philadelphia, PA, poster, circa 1950s (Box 55, Folder 28)
    - The Irish Reel (Drawing), 1913 (Box Shared Tamiment 162, Folder 6)
    - Irish Show of the Year, Irish Center, Philadelphia, flyer, Dec 3, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 30)
    - John McCormack - Symphony Hall Boston Program, 1923 (Box 58, Folder 25)
    - "Judge's Library - All Sorts", 1894 (Box 58, Folder 18)
    - Life Magazine "Irish In America", 1961 (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 3)
    - Martin Costello Orchestra, flyer, circa 1960s (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Middle Lake, Killarney (photo), undated (Box 55, Folder 33)
    - Moonan, George and Mother, Mary Ann Tiernan Moonan (photo), Aug 31, 1928 (Box 55, Folder 34)
    - National Celtic Association, Chicago, circular, Aug 9, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - The "New Irish Movement", undated (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - "New Year's Eve in Ireland" drawing, Jan 15, 1870 (Box 55, Folder 26)
    - The New York Clipper Newspaper, 1891 (Box Shared Tamiment 162, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1880, 1887, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 1)
    - Notebook with Theater Cast Lists, undated (Box 58, Folder 28)
    - Pat Taggart's Furniture City, Philadelpia, Advertisement, circa 1950s (Box 55, Folder 29)
    - Photograph - Unidentified Group, undated (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Poster of "Erin" Statue, undated (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - Print matter and artwork, various (16 items), 1877-1953 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - "Puck's Library", 1892 (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - "Speak or Die!" Weekly National Press, March 1892 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Thomas Moore (prints), undated (Box 58, Folder 26)
    - Three Little Maids from County Cork (photo), 1929 (Box 55, Folder 35)
    - Tobacco/Cigar Box Art (12 items); includes images of Peggy O'Moore, Peggy O'Neal, Robert Emmet, Denis O'Sullivan, 1868, undated (Box 56, Folder 15)